<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES">
  <item>
    <name>Javelin of Lightning</name>
    <type>M</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
    <dmgType>P</dmgType>
    <property>T</property>
    <range>30/120</range>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>	This javelin is a magic weapon. When you hurl it and speak its command word, it transforms into a bolt of lightning, forming a line 5 feet wide that extends out from you to a target within 120 feet. Each creature in the line excluding you and the target must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 lightning damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The lightning bolt turns back into a javelin when it reaches the target. Make a ranged weapon attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes damage from the javelin plus 4d6 lightning damage.</text>
    <text>The javelin's property can't be used again until the next dawn. In the meantime, the javelin can still be used as a magic weapon.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
    <text />
    <text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 178</text>
    <roll>4d6</roll>
  </item>
</compendium>